

ZIYAD MUHAMMAD

E-mail: ziyad.muhammad91@yahoo.com

Phone: 01778660055, 01920950259

Permanent Address: 399/2/C, South Paikpara, Kallyanpur, Mirpur, Dhaka-1216

Profile:

Enthusiastic, results oriented HR professional with general experience in planning and directing all areas of Human Resources that includes but is not limited to: recruitment, HR Operations, Organizational Development. employment law, employee relations, on-boarding, payroll, performance management, policy & procedures, safety & supervision.

Work Experiences

1. JAPFA COMFEED BANGLADESH PTE LTD. (A concern of JAPFA Comfeed Indonesia Tbk) (September 2020 – Till Now)

Position: Assistant Manager, Human Resources

Job Description:

- Planning and executing recruiting activities that result in the hiring of the right talent across levels.
- Responsible for the preparation of Manpower Plan in consultation with the respective HODs.
- Functioning as a SPOC (Single Point Of Contact) for all Recruitment & Selection related activities.
- Develop and Update Organogram on timely manner.
- Spear heading the Job Description across the organization, creating & finalizing the job description based on position after consulting the HOD.
- Updating & Maintaining the recruitment Tracker and other reports as per the set frequency, preparing reports related to open positions, TAT (Turn Around Time), Projected Headcount etc.
- Preparing SOPs, processes related to Recruitment & Selection & reviewing it on a timely basis.
- Conduct employee induction and introductory training so that new employees are quickly integrated into the organization.
- Conduct CFL (Closed feedback loop) session with employees.
- Vendor management for employee benefits & facilities (Banking, Corporate SIM management, Health & Life insurance)
- Leading Compensation & Benefits team to execute monthly payroll processing, verify monthly inputs for
 payroll processing, on time salary disbursement, with adhere appropriate compliance, balance payroll
 accounts by resolving payroll discrepancies before final processing, ensuring AIT deduction by coordinating
 with finance team, personal loan management.
- Facilitate employee life cycle management (Confirmation, employee transfers, promotions & employee separation etc.)
- Conduct on time delivery of different HR referral letters/certificates (promotion letter, Increment Letter, Transfer Letter, NOC, Experience, Employment certificates etc.)
- Monitor & update HRIS on timely basis.
- Deal with grievances & counsel employees with various issues.
- Actively engage employer branding activities.
- Contributing to the restructuring of departments to increase efficiency and align activities with business objectives.
- Optimizing personnel utilization by increasing cross-functionality and interdepartmental cooperation.
- Conduct PBK (Product Base Training) quarterly to increase the product knowledge for non-technical sales people.

2. UPS (United Parcel Service) (March 2018 – September 2020)

Position: Senior Executive, HR Operations

Job Description:

- Develop and implement HR strategies and initiatives aligned with the overall business strategy.
- Support current and future business needs through the development, engagement, motivation and preservation of human capital.
- Develop and monitor overall HR strategies, systems, tactics and procedures across the organization.
- Measuring the impact of interventions on staff performance, efficiency, employee retention, and job satisfaction.
- Advising executives and senior managers and recommending efficient and cost-effective solutions for identified challenges.
- Develop a network of potential future hires (e.g. past applicants and referred candidates).
- Measure key recruitment metrics, like source of hire and time-to-hire.
- Monitor & Manage DreamApps (HRIS system) and ensure functionality of system.
- Organize and/or attend career fairs, assessment centers or other events.
- Recommending new policies, approaches, and procedures.
- Maintains the work structure by updating job requirements and job descriptions for all positions.
- Conduct on-boarding of new employees through ensuring full logistical support, check relevant joining documents and conduct reference checking of previous education & experience
- Facilitate employee life cycle management (confirmation, employee transfers, promotions and employee separation etc.) to meet business requirements
- Conduct on time delivery of different HR referral letters/certificates (Promotion letter, Increment letter, Transfer Letter, NOC, Experience, Employment certificates etc.)
- Lead the salary administration process & Employee Separation Process.
- Ensure that compensation practices are in compliance with current laws and regulations.
- Coordinate PMS along with HOHR.
- Responsible for entire Medical Insurance & Life insurance of the Group.
- Look after the entire Head Office & Dhaka Branches Office Administration.
- Conduct quarterly training session for non-management employee.
- Maintaining training calendar & register for non-management employees.
- Arrange monthly surprise visit to All Branches.

3. Le Meridien Dhaka, A concern of Marriott International Inc. (May 2015 - March 2018)

Position: HR Assistant (Grade 3)

Job Description:

- To be aware of current vacancies and to respond to and screen telephone and walk-in inquiries.
- Ensure 100% reference checks, police verification & pre-employment medical check-up for the selected candidates.
- Prepare personal action form, complete contract of employment and compile induction kit.
- Respond to incoming application within two weeks of receipt, and unsuccessful interviews within one week of their unsuitability.
- Maintain and update HRIS with 100% accuracy.
- Compile new job contracts for internal changes in status, transfers and promotions before the effective date and ensure via a tracking system that these new contracts have been signed before effective date.
- Work with the selected insurance company for associate hospitalization and group life insurance coverage.
- Track all internal movements and report quarterly percentages to Director of Human Resources.
- To be familiar with and knowledgeable of the Labor Code for your own understanding and to advise Associates of conditions.
- Ensure Human Resource Policy Manuals are maintained and up-to-date.
- Respond to Associate requests for statements of service/earnings and take responsibility for other general inquiries.
- File all payroll/personnel paperwork within two weeks of receipt and maintain accuracy of all files.
- Ensure that all new employees attend the Hotel Orientation program.

- In conjunction with Department Heads, develop departmental on the job training schedules that meet departmental operating objectives.
- Assist HOD to develop and administer employee recognition and relation.
- Administer SW careers & GMAP as per Starwood guideline.
- Ensure all associates receive their due remuneration on a timely basis.
- Verify all payroll payments are processed in accordance with Company Policy and applicable labor regulations. Maintain accurate Payroll records.
- Collate and check payroll information from original sources.
- Complete salaried and wage payroll data input.
- Download and update Associate payroll and benefits data, producing pay slips, reports for management information.
- Check timesheets against rosters.
- Take part in monthly payroll audit from Controllers.
- Co-ordinate and maintain group life insurance and health insurance as per the Labor code and regulations.

4. Confidence Electric Limited (a concern of Confidence group of Industries) (August 2013 – April 2015)

Position: Executive, PSHR

Job Description:

- To collect & verify manpower requisitions as per approved Manpower plan & Prepare Vacancy List.
- Make correspondence regarding appointment, confirmation, increment, promotion, transfer, termination etc.
- Plan job descriptions for recruitment.
- To maintain and update CV Bank for all positions time to time.
- To prepare, circulate the Interview Schedule and conduct the same in the prescribed manner.
- To verify selected candidates all academic and other relevant documents and get prepare the profiles for management approval.
- Conduct Orientation and training session for new employee.
- Ensure proper effectiveness of Human Resource & Administration activities in the office.
- Develop & maintain personnel record systems in accordance with current legislation.
- Co-ordinate with other departments regarding the effective implementation of HR policies & Procedure.
- To prepare update report and maintain all HRIS is respect with Recruitment, Selection, Placement and follow up.
- Conduct exit interviews to identify reasons for employee separation.
- To prepare & update report and maintain all HRIS is respect with Recruitment, Selection, Placement and follow up.
- To prepare monthly salary & attendance statement.
- Monitor the Consumption of office consumable goods.
- Communicate with the concerned agent for preparing ID cards, Business Cards, Stationary& Printing Items.

Trainings:

- Data Handling Procedure.
- Service Culture Pathway.
- Negotiation Skill.
- Time Management & Punctuality.
- Secrets of Becoming a Trainer.

Awards / Nomination / Appreciation:

- Nominated for the associate of the month on the category of Outstanding Care for Associates on Nov'2016.
- Awarded for the associate of the month on the category of Outstanding Care for Associates on Feb'2017.
- Received LM Pride Pin from General Manager.

Projects:

- Successfully took over the payroll system of 342 employees from third party vendors.
- Implemented the customized attendance software along with rosters & OT calculation.
- Successfully run the first ever Role Reversal Program on Le Meridien Dhaka.
- LM Associate Handbook.

Education:

MBA

American International University, Bangladesh Major in Human Resource Management.

CGPA: 3.60 / 4 Year: 2015

HSC

Dhaka Commerce College

CGPA: 4.30 Year: 2008

BBA

American International University, Bangladesh Major in Human Resource Management.

CGPA: 3.68 / 4 Year: 2012

SSC

Scholars School & College

CGPA: 4.06 Year: 2006

Skills:

- Strong communication & interpersonal skills
- Highly organized
- Trustworthy and discreet
- Team work
- Patience, integrity and sensitivity
- Flexible and adaptable
- Good at building relationships and able to influence others

Personal Details:

Fathers Name: MR. Muhammad Abdul Hye

• Date of Birth: 26 September 1991

Home District: Habigonj

References:

• References available upon request